<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://hasnainiitd.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://hasnainiitd.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2023-03-19T04:34:15+00:00</updated><id>https://hasnainiitd.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Hasnain Ali</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Intelligent Airport Congestion Management</title><link href="https://hasnainiitd.github.io/blog/2022/NCODEX-AU/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Intelligent Airport Congestion Management"/><published>2022-11-05T15:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-11-05T15:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://hasnainiitd.github.io/blog/2022/NCODEX-AU</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hasnainiitd.github.io/blog/2022/NCODEX-AU/"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UClMx1dgrXYFbELdDp7B7SzQ/videos">PhD Talks by NcodeX</a> is a platform that brings out PhD researchers in STEM industry and academia from universities around the world to talk innovation. Prestigious PhD students from universities around the world, are hand-picked to disseminate their research and recent breakthrough findings into general and professional communities, to talk innovation and inter-desciplinarity of STEM research, and how their research bring sustainability in future.</p> ]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Thesis-Talks"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Online Zoom, Australia]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Data Driven And Learning Based Approaches For Integrated Landside Airside Operations Optimization</title><link href="https://hasnainiitd.github.io/blog/2022/HIT-NTU/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Data Driven And Learning Based Approaches For Integrated Landside Airside Operations Optimization"/><published>2022-11-02T15:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-11-02T15:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://hasnainiitd.github.io/blog/2022/HIT-NTU</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hasnainiitd.github.io/blog/2022/HIT-NTU/"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/0xta7wep3X42NihUMqzGyv">High Impact Thesis Podcast</a> is a platform that hosts PhD students, Researchers, and Professors, from Nanyang Technological University (NTU Singapore), to talk about their research and share their work experience.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Thesis-Talks"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nanyang Technological University, Singapore]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Death by PowerPoint- Online Workshop on Making Effective Presentations</title><link href="https://hasnainiitd.github.io/blog/2022/MAEGSC-NTU/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Death by PowerPoint- Online Workshop on Making Effective Presentations"/><published>2022-02-21T16:40:16+00:00</published><updated>2022-02-21T16:40:16+00:00</updated><id>https://hasnainiitd.github.io/blog/2022/MAEGSC-NTU</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hasnainiitd.github.io/blog/2022/MAEGSC-NTU/"><![CDATA[ <p>Scientific presentations play a very important role in the life of a researcher during PhD years and beyond, which unfortunately many researchers do not appreciate enough. Not surprisingly, it is a huge stress to look at most PowerPoint slides.</p> <hr/> <blockquote> Depending on the “design” skills of the speaker and audience’s taste slides create different emotions from a slight annoyance to physical sickness. </blockquote> <p>The workshop covered universal design principles, templates, colors, typefaces, slides’ typography, use of photos and pictograms, composition rules and ways to create clear and meaningful charts and diagrams. Participants were divided into groups and supported by office bearers and other volunteers to apply the learned principles themselves using an application like Google Slides, followed by a short discussion on how their slides can be compared to a “model” slide. Refer <a href="https://hasanain-ali.github.io/files/Death_by_PowerPoint_Workshop.pdf">Online Workshop on Making Effective Presentations</a> for more details.</p> ]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="workshop"/><category term="talks"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nanyang Technological University, Singapore]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Data Exploration &amp;amp; Visualisation Workshop With Python</title><link href="https://hasnainiitd.github.io/blog/2021/IES-ASME-NTU/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Data Exploration &amp;amp; Visualisation Workshop With Python"/><published>2021-10-14T15:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-10-14T15:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://hasnainiitd.github.io/blog/2021/IES-ASME-NTU</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hasnainiitd.github.io/blog/2021/IES-ASME-NTU/"><![CDATA[<p>The purpose of this Python workshop is to introduce more advanced Python programming for data science to NTU undergraduates. It is hoped that this introductory workshop to Python Programming for Data Science may spark interest in the participants to delve deeper into programming and data science in general.</p> <p>In this 3-hour long workshop, I discussed and demonstrated to NTU undergraduates the data exploration and visualization capabilities using Python (numpy, pandas, matplotlib and seaborn). This was followed by a hands-on session wherein participants were tasked to perform data visualization tasks using <a href="https://worldhappiness.report/ed/2021/">World-Happiness-Report-Data</a>. Refer <a href="https://hasanain-ali.github.io/files/IES_ASME_NTU_poster.jpg">Data Exploration &amp; Visualisation Workshop</a> for more details.</p> ]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="workshop"/><category term="talks"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nanyang Technological University, Singapore]]></summary></entry></feed>